<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chamsii Mouhib</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content on Chamsii Mouhib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Certifications exam notes</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/11/certifications-exam-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/11/certifications-exam-notes/</guid><description>Some notes I took during my certifications journey: RHCE Exam Notes and tips
RHCSA Exam Notes and tips
AWS CCP Exam Notes and tips</description></item><item><title>Understanding CI/CD</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/10/understanding-ci/cd/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/10/understanding-ci/cd/</guid><description>0 . 1 What is CI/CD : CI/CD is an automated and reliable process for software development and delivery.&amp;amp;* CI/CD’s frequent testing reduces code errors and defects. The main concepts attributed to CI/CD are continuos integration, delivery and deployment. ⇒ The main goal is to reduce the risk involved in deploying software.
0 . 2 What’s the difference between CI &amp;amp; CD &amp;amp; CD : Countinous integration is an automation process for developers, which is new code changes to an app are regularly built, tested and merged to a shared repository.</description></item><item><title>Deploying NGINX web server with kubernetes</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/projects/project00.txt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/projects/project00.txt/</guid><description>Hello, We already know that with Kubernetes you can easily deploy and manage NGINX across a cluster of nodes, ensuring high availability and efficient resource utilization. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the steps involved in deploying NGINX with Kubernetes and how it can benefit your web hosting infrastructure.
1 - Create nginx-deployement.yaml file :
apiVersion : apps/v1 kind: Deployment metadata: name: nginx labels: app: nginx spec: replicas: 1 selector: matchlabels: app: nginx template: metadata: labels: app: nginx spec: containers: - name: nginx image: nginx ports: - containerPort: 80 2 - Create the deployment : kubectl create -f dep.</description></item><item><title>Bypassing common jinja2 filters</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/08/bypassing-common-jinja2-filters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/08/bypassing-common-jinja2-filters/</guid><description>What is SSTI? SSTI is an injection vulnerability, similar to other injection vulnerabilities it occurs when unsanitized user input is directly processed by the application or more specifically the template engine.
Depending on the template engine being used the impact can vary, some of the issues range from:
Data exposure (application secrets) Cross Site Scripting Remote Code execution String filters</description></item><item><title/><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/projects.txt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/projects.txt/</guid><description>During my acadamic years in TEK-UP, I&amp;rsquo;ve done projects that helped me a lot improving my skills in coding and with understanding things in depth.
Bank System : Desktop based Banking Application using JAVA, Netbeans, Swing , XAMPP , mysql
GitHub Link
Game Launcher : A game launcher interface with python.
GitHub Link
Loca Cars : Developement of a software for managing a car rental company online.
Frontend : HTML, CSS, JavaScript Backend : PHP DataBase : mySQL, xampp server Salary Management : Basic application to manage employee salaries through a C++ program.</description></item><item><title>.\chxmxii.ps1</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/about.txt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/about.txt/</guid><description>Hey there, I am Chamsi Mouhib aka chxmxii a driven and ambitious Cybersecurity Engineering student with a passion for Cloud and Cybersecurity, an enthusiast of automation tools, and actively involved in the cybersecurity community, participating in CTFs with a focus on web challenges. With a strong desire to learn and grow, I am always eager to expand my skill set and knowledge by learning from others.
Throughout this site, you will find various articles I have authored involving cloud technologies (Automation tools, IaC, K8S etc.</description></item></channel></rss>