<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sysadmin on Chamsii Mouhib</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/tags/sysadmin/</link><description>Recent content in Sysadmin on Chamsii Mouhib</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/tags/sysadmin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KKE Jenkins Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-jenkins-challenges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-jenkins-challenges/</guid><description>Jenkins Installation The DevOps team of xFusionCorp Industries is planning to setup some CI/CD pipelines. After several meetings they have decided to use Jenkins server. So, we need to setup a Jenkins Server as soon as possible. Please complete the task as per requirements mentioned below: Install jenkins on jenkins server using yum utility only, and start its service. You might face timeout issue while starting the Jenkins service, please refer this link for help.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Kubernetes Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-kubernetes-challenges/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-kubernetes-challenges/</guid><description>Kuberentes time check pod The Nautilus DevOps team want to create a time check pod in a particular Kubernetes namespace and record the logs. This might be initially used only for testing purposes, but later can be implemented in an existing cluster. Please find more details below about the task and perform it. Create a pod called time-check in the datacenter namespace. This pod should run a container called time-check, container should use the busybox image with latest tag only and remember to mention tag i.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Ansible Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-ansible-challenges/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-ansible-challenges/</guid><description>Ansible Unarchive Module One of the DevOps team members has created an ZIP archive on jump host in Stratos DC that needs to be extracted and copied over to all app servers in Stratos DC itself. Because this is a routine task, the Nautilus DevOps team has suggested automating it. We can use Ansible since we have been using it for other automation tasks. Below you can find more details about the task: We have an inventory file under /home/thor/ansible directory on jump host, which should have all the app servers added already.</description></item><item><title>KKE Linux Challenges P2</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-linux-challenges-p2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/08/kke-linux-challenges-p2/</guid><description>Web Server Security During a recent security audit, the application security team of xFusionCorp Industries found security issues with the Apache web server on Nautilus App Server 1 server in Stratos DC. They have listed several security issues that need to be fixed on this server. Please apply the security settings below: a. On Nautilus App Server 1 it was identified that the Apache web server is exposing the version number.</description></item><item><title>KKE Linux Challenges P1</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/05/kke-linux-challenges-p1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2023/05/kke-linux-challenges-p1/</guid><description>Linux TimeZones Setting During the daily standup, it was pointed out that the timezone across Nautilus Application Servers in Stratos Datacenter doesn&amp;rsquo;t match with that of the local datacenter&amp;rsquo;s timezone, which is America/Blanc-Sablon. solution : #ssh to app server 1 account and switch to root sshpass -p Ir0nM@n ssh -o StrictHostKeyChecking=no tony@stapp01 sudo su - # change the timezone to America/Blanc-Sablon timedatectl set-timezone America/Blanc-Sablon #Verify timedatectl Linux User Files There was some users data copied on Nautilus App Server 1 at /home/usersdata location by the Nautilus production support team in Stratos DC.</description></item><item><title>RingZer0CTF Sysadmin Track</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/04/ringzer0ctf-sysadmin-track/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/posts/2022/04/ringzer0ctf-sysadmin-track/</guid><description>SysAdmin Part 1 ┌──(kali㉿kali)-[~] └─$ sshpass -p VNZDDLq2x9qXCzVdABbR1HOtz ssh -o StrictHostKeyChecking=no morpheus@challenges.ringzer0team.com -p 10089 Warning: Permanently added &amp;#39;[challenges.ringzer0team.com]:10089&amp;#39; (ED25519) to the list of known hosts. 888888ba oo d8888888P a8888a d888888P 88 8b .d8&amp;#39; d8 8b 88 88aaaa8P dP 88d888b. .d8888b. .d8&amp;#39; .d8888b. 88d888b. 88 P 88 88 .d8888b. .d8888b. 88d8b.d8b. 88 8b. 88 88 88 88 88 .d8&amp;#39; 88ooood8 88 88 88 d 88 88 88ooood8 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 88 d8&amp;#39; 88.</description></item></channel></rss>