<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jenkins on Mouhib CHVMSI</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/tags/jenkins/</link><description>Recent content in Jenkins on Mouhib CHVMSI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/tags/jenkins/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>KKE - Jenkins Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/writeups/post04.txt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/writeups/post04.txt/</guid><description>Jenkins Installation The DevOps team of xFusionCorp Industries is planning to setup some CI/CD pipelines. After several meetings they have decided to use Jenkins server. So, we need to setup a Jenkins Server as soon as possible. Please complete the task as per requirements mentioned below: Install jenkins on jenkins server using yum utility only, and start its service. You might face timeout issue while starting the Jenkins service, please refer this link for help.</description></item><item><title>Automating the implementation of a DevSecOps Pipeline - PART 01</title><link>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/projects/project01.txt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.github.io/portfolio/projects/project01.txt/</guid><description>Picture this: software development practices evolving like a Pokémon on steroids, giving birth to the legendary concepts of DevOps and its sidekick, DevSecOps. They&amp;rsquo;re like Batman and Robin, but for software development. DevOps focuses on collaboration and integration between development and operations teams, turbocharging software delivery speed and reliability. And then, DevSecOps enters the scene, adding a sprinkle of security practices throughout the entire software development lifecycle. It&amp;rsquo;s like adding a secret agent to the mix – shaken, not stirred.</description></item></channel></rss>