<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hugo 101 on Mouhib CHVMSI</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/series/hugo-101/</link><description>Recent content in Hugo 101 on Mouhib CHVMSI</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chxmxii.tech/series/hugo-101/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Boost Your App's Security with this open-source tool.</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/posts/2023/11/boost-your-apps-security-with-this-open-source-tool./</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/posts/2023/11/boost-your-apps-security-with-this-open-source-tool./</guid><description>Ever wondered how to make your app more secure without diving into complex tech jargon? Meet CrowdSec, an open-source tool that&amp;rsquo;s here to simplify things for you. In this blog, I&amp;rsquo;ll take you through a beginner-friendly lab to enhance your app&amp;rsquo;s security. No need to be a tech guru – let&amp;rsquo;s make your app safer together!
&amp;lt;/ /&amp;gt; CrowdSec – What is it and how does it work? So, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard about CrowdSec, and it sounds kinda cool, right?</description></item><item><title>Certifications exam notes</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/posts/2023/09/certifications-exam-notes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/posts/2023/09/certifications-exam-notes/</guid><description>These are some useful notes I gathered while pursuing my certifications RHCE EX294 Notes and tips
RHCCS EX188 Notes and tips
RHCSA EX200 Notes and tips
AWS CCP Exam Notes and tips</description></item><item><title>KKE - Kubernetes Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup10.txt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup10.txt/</guid><description>Create Pods in Kubernetes Cluster The Nautilus DevOps team has started practicing some pods and services deployment on Kubernetes platform as they are planning to migrate most of their applications on Kubernetes platform. Recently one of the team members has been assigned a task to create a pod as per details mentioned below: Create a pod named pod-httpd using httpd image with latest tag only and remember to mention the tag i.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Ansible Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup09.txt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup09.txt/</guid><description>{ CHXMXII } Ansible Unarchive Module One of the DevOps team members has created an ZIP archive on jump host in Stratos DC that needs to be extracted and copied over to all app servers in Stratos DC itself. Because this is a routine task, the Nautilus DevOps team has suggested automating it. We can use Ansible since we have been using it for other automation tasks. Below you can find more details about the task: We have an inventory file under /home/thor/ansible directory on jump host, which should have all the app servers added already.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Jenkins Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup04.txt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup04.txt/</guid><description>Jenkins Installation The DevOps team of xFusionCorp Industries is planning to setup some CI/CD pipelines. After several meetings they have decided to use Jenkins server. So, we need to setup a Jenkins Server as soon as possible. Please complete the task as per requirements mentioned below: Install jenkins on jenkins server using yum utility only, and start its service. You might face timeout issue while starting the Jenkins service, please refer this link for help.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Git Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup01.txt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup01.txt/</guid><description>Git Install and Create Bare Repository The Nautilus development team shared requirements with the DevOps team regarding new application development.—specifically, they want to set up a Git repository for that project. Create a Git repository on Storage server in Stratos DC as per details given below:
Install git package using yum on Storage server. After that create a bare repository /opt/blog.git (make sure to use exact name). Solution $ sshpass -p Bl@kW ssh -o StrictHostKeyChecking=no natasha@ststor01 $ sudo yum install -y git $ sudo mkdir /opt/blog.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Linux Challenges P2</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup07.txt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup07.txt/</guid><description>Web Server Security During a recent security audit, the application security team of xFusionCorp Industries found security issues with the Apache web server on Nautilus App Server 1 server in Stratos DC. They have listed several security issues that need to be fixed on this server. Please apply the security settings below: a. On Nautilus App Server 1 it was identified that the Apache web server is exposing the version number.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Docker Challenges</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup08.txt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup08.txt/</guid><description>Docker Ports Mapping The Nautilus DevOps team is planning to host an application on a nginx-based container. There are number of tickets already been created for similar tasks. One of the tickets has been assigned to set up a nginx container on Application Server 1 in Stratos Datacenter. Please perform the task as per details mentioned below: a. Pull nginx:stable docker image on Application Server 1. b. Create a container named cluster using the image you pulled.</description></item><item><title>KKE - Linux Challenges P1</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup03.txt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup03.txt/</guid><description>Linux TimeZones Setting During the daily standup, it was pointed out that the timezone across Nautilus Application Servers in Stratos Datacenter doesn&amp;rsquo;t match with that of the local datacenter&amp;rsquo;s timezone, which is America/Blanc-Sablon. solution : #ssh to app server 1 account and switch to root sshpass -p Ir0nM@n ssh -o StrictHostKeyChecking=no tony@stapp01 sudo su - # change the timezone to America/Blanc-Sablon timedatectl set-timezone America/Blanc-Sablon #Verify timedatectl Linux User Files There was some users data copied on Nautilus App Server 1 at /home/usersdata location by the Nautilus production support team in Stratos DC.</description></item><item><title>Terraform Challenge Series - Challenge 1</title><link>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup06.txt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://chxmxii.tech/writeups/writeup06.txt/</guid><description>In this challenge we will deploy several Kubernetes resources using terraform. Utilize /root/terraform_challenge directory to store your Terraform configuration files. Note: kubectl is already installed on the host, you can check your deployments in the usual way.
Architecture : Solution : Controlplane We will start by installing terraform in the controlplane node apt update apt install unzip -y curl -L -o /tmp/terraform_1.1.5_linux_amd64.zip https://releases.hashicorp.com/terraform/1.1.5/terraform_1.1.5_linux_amd64.zip unzip -d /usr/local/bin /tmp/terraform_1.1.5_linux_amd64.zip which terraform terrafomr --version cd /root/terraform_challenge Kubernetes-provider for the kubernets provider we will configure it within provider.</description></item></channel></rss>